Mohammad Ali Momen



mamomen1996@gmail.com



+989399589232



linkedin.com/in/mamomen1996



https://github.com/mamomen1996

Summary

Full-Stack Machine Learning Engineer with more than 4 years of practical experience in Python, R and Java programming languages.

- * Experience
- 4 years of total Software Engineering experience, with 1 years in Machine Learning Engineering

Experienced ML engineer trained in Python, R, Java, SQL and Linux.

* Career highlights

Design, Development and Implementation the "Online insurance premium list receipt and payment system" which is one of the most important online services of "National Social Security Organization" of I.R.Iran

This service process almost 1.5 million insurance lists containing over 20 million people information per every month.

The project had been on hold for 7 years when I joined and I delivered it's first version in just 4 months.

I received 2 certificates of appreciation for this project from CEO

Have worked in agile environments with teammates from 5 to 15 poeple

Experience



Java Full-Stack Web Developer

Tamin (ICT & Management Consultancy)

Dec 2020 - Mar 2023 (2 years 4 months)

- * Let the transition to fully-online service of insurance list receipt and payment by implementing an Insurance List System. 70% reduction in client visits to insurance branches and 20% reduction in administrative costs and 30% cost of labor at the National Level.
- * Develop and maintain Java EE applications for user-management, contributing to the successful implementation of 15+ OAuth features.
- * Designed and implementation secure authentication and authorization mechanisms using Java EE technologies, resulting in a 20% reduction in unauthorized access attempts.

Java Backend Web Developer

مكتب شريف Maktab Sharif

Jun 2020 - Dec 2020 (7 months)

* Learned the Spring Boot framework in 6 months.

- * Carrying out more than 20 projects based on Java core, Spring MVC, Spring Boot during the bootcamp.
- * Assisted in the development and maintenance of Java applications using Spring framework, contributing to the successful completion of 20+ development tasks within assigned deadlines.

Education

A-aubaiiau I

Azarbaijan University of Tarbiat Moallem

Bachelor of Science - BS, Physics Oct 2014 - Oct 2018

Allameh Helli school

High School Diploma, Mathematics and Physics Oct 2010 - Oct 2014

Licenses & Certifications

- Advanced Algorithmic Thinking and Data Structure Quera
- مکتب شریف Java-Spring Development Maktab Sharif مکتب
- Data Science Tose'e Higher Education Institute
- Advanced Data Science Tose'e Higher Education Institute
- Artificial Intelligence Part

Skills

Data Analysis • Deep Learning • Machine Learning • Artificial Intelligence (AI) • Data Visualization • Python (Programming Language) • R (Programming Language) • SQL • Java • Linux